Madison Bertis

Web developer with experience in fast-paced work environments and an interest in debugging and maintaining server-side systems. Independent learner with a strong drive to accomplish goals and share knowledge with others. Background includes training peers and coworkers on best practices, extensive customer service, and management of a local symphony's ticketing website.

Projects

Angular Application / CareerFoundry

April 2021 - May 2021

- Built a robust and responsive client-side component of my "movies" application based on its existing server-side code using Angular and Angular Material.
- Documentation generated with TypeDoc; generated technical documentation for the API using JSDoc.

Chat App / CareerFoundry

March 2021 - April 2021

- Built a chat app for mobile devices using React Native that allows users to message one another and share information such as images and location.
- Responsive and aesthetic UI created through implementation of GiftedChat.
- Utilized Firebase database for storing messages online and to allow users to access messages while offline.
- Created and ran application using Expo CLI and tested with Android emulators/iOS simulators.

Meet App / CareerFoundry

February 2021 - March 2021

- Built a serverless progressive web application with React using a test-driven development (TDD) technique.
- Utilized Google Calendar API to fetch upcoming events.
- Implemented options for visualizing and filtering data based on location.
- Developed user stories for each feature of the app.

React Application / CareerFoundry

December 2020 - February 2021

- Used React to create the client-side component of my "movies" web application.
- Utilized state routing to navigate between views in this single-page application.
- Used Parcel as initial build tool.
- Written in React Redux and utilized Bootstrap to create an optimized UI.

myFlix API / CareerFoundry

November 2020 - December 2020

- Created the server-side component of a "movies" web application.
- Utilized RESTful architecture.
- Implemented Node.js, Express, and Axios requests.
- Created documentation for all URL endpoints.
- Database built using MongoDB and tested in Postman.
- Deployed on Heroku.

Pokedex App / CareerFoundry

October 2020 - November 2020

- Created a small web application using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Data is loaded from an external API.
- Allowed users to view a list of all Pokemon, filter Pokemon by name, and learn more about each Pokemon by selecting an individual listing.

Portfolio Website / CareerFoundry

October 2020 - October 2020

- Created a website entirely from scratch using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript basics.
- Implemented Bootstrap to make site responsive and thematically consistent

Work Experience

Spokane Symphony - May 2019 - June 2021 - Spokane, WA

Assistant Box Office Manager

- Managed the ticketing website for the Spokane Symphony and Martin Woldson Theater at The Fox.
- Planned and conducted staff training on Tessitura ticketing system.
- Built all events in Tessitura according to specifications given by Symphony or outside tour agencies.
- Lead back-end maintenance of Tessitura to ensure ticketing system operated as expected.

Spokane Symphony - September 2018 - May 2019 - Spokane, WA

Box Office Associate

- Worked on a hand-selected team to implement Tessitura ticketing system in the box office.
- Assisted customers over-the-phone and in-person.
- Managed subscription services.

Contact

madisonbertis@gmail.com

509.850.6960

Spokane, WA

https://www.madisonbertis.com/

Skills

HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript

MongoDB

SQL and PostgreSQL

TypeScript

Angular

React, Redux, React Native

jQuery Node.js

Bootstrap

MERN Stack

Express

Node Package Manager (NPM)

API Configuration using RESTful Architecture

Testing in Postman

Deployment to Netlify and Heroku

GitHub/Git Version Control

Web Ethics and Data Security

Test-Driven Development (TDD)

Progressive Web Applications (PWA)

Education

CareerFoundry

October 2020 - May 2021

Full-Stack Immersion Certificate

CareerFoundry

October 2020 - October 2020

Intro to Frontend Development Certificate

University of Puget Sound

August 2013 - May 2017

Bachelor of Science in Chemistry